Guide to the Cornell University Library records, [ca.1868]-2010.
Cornell University Library records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Library records, [ca.1868]-2010.
13-1-1082
Cornell University. Library. Administration.
117.2 Cubic Feet.
Correspondence, financial documents, printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence relating to the development and administration of the library, general administrative files, administrative files of Librarians, financial records, statistical reports, and grant files.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence relating to the development and administration of the library, general administrative files, administrative files of Librarians Otto Kinkeldey and Stephen McCarthy, financial records, statistical reports, and grant files. Also, records pertaining to the construction of the John M. Olin Library, including correspondence and reports of the Ad Hoc Committee on the Library Building Program; preliminary drawings; architectural drawings and blueprints; booklets, brochures, and papers relating to the dedication ceremonies; Library of Congress files, 1958-1986; ALA and ARL files, 1949-1985; Collection Development and Management Project files and user survey, 1978-1981; file relating to Cornell's decision to join RLG, 1978-1979; scrapbook of clippings of events connected with the library, 1984-1990; results of a poll of library employees, ca. 1975; files of the Librarian (primarily Louis Martin and Gormly Miller) relating to departments in Olin Library including Circulation, History of Science, Icelandic, Interlibrary Loan, Manuscripts and University Archives, Maps, Microtexts, and Newspapers, the New York Historical Resources Center, and Reference, 1968-1989.
RLG files include materials relating to BibTech, Conspectus, Shared Cataloging Program, Preservation Committee, and Cultural Materials Alliance, ca. 1984-2006
Also recognition by the Council for Advancement and Support of Education (CASE) for superior accomplishments, 1983; and Libraries at Cornell brochure, 1984.
Also, photo album of a 1990 visit by Asian dignitaries, a 1980 User Survey, a code book of detailed work done by several departments (1891-1923) including special collection bookplates, and slides and audiocassettes describing the library.
Also Excellence in Academic Libraries Award certificate from ACRL (Association of College & Research Libraries) and library brochure.
Memorabilia includes pen used to sign an cooperation agreement with Tsinghua University in China, 2009 and various ribbons, buttons, etc.
Files of Karen Calhoun on the Library's Models for Academic Support (MAS 2010) project, 2002-2004; Library Management Team, 2001-2006; and Technical Services Executive Group files, 1999-2006.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Kaser, David, 1924-; Kinkeldey, Otto, 1878-1966.; Martin, Louis E.; McCarthy, Stephen A. (Stephen Anthony), 1908-1990.; Miller, J. Gormly.; Seznec, Alain.; American Library Association.; Association of Research Libraries.; Carl A. Kroch Library (Cornell University); Cornell University. Libraries.; Cornell University. Library. Department of Rare Books.; Cornell University. Library. Department of Manuscripts and University Archives.; Library of Congress.; Research Libraries Group.
Titles:
Cornell University register.
Subjects:
Academic libraries -- Administration.; Academic libraries -- Statistics.; Library administration.; Library architecture.; Library buildings.; Library finance.; Academic librarians -- New York (State) -- Ithaca.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted to permission of office of origin.
Boxes 58-70, 73 are not restricted.
RELATED MATERIALS
See also Cornell University Library Records, #13-1-17.
NOTES
Includes collection #13-1-1287.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Link to a partial finding aid
Series II. Grant Files
CONTAINER LIST
- Link to a partial finding aid.
  Not all the material in the collection is covered by this guide.
- Grant Files
  These files are ordered chronologically by the dates of the official grant period. The files within each category therefore have dates both before and after the date of the grant, as preliminary and followup information is included in these files. In some cases where there are several files for one grant, the files are not arranged chronologically, but are instead grouped by complementary materials.
  Grant titles appear in bold, with corresponding folders below them.
  - Dean, J. Cornell/Xerox Joint Study in Digital Preservation, October 10, 1988 - June 3, 1991 (Box 128)
    CPA
  - Dean, J. Cornell/Xerox Joint Study in Digital Preservation, October 10, 1988 - June 3, 1991 (Box 128)
  - Xerox Proposal, October 10, 1988 - November 1, 1989 (Box 128, Folder 1)
  - Xerox Project - Folder 1, October 1, 1989 - June 3, 1991 (Box 128, Folder 2)
  - Xerox Project - Folder 2, November 1, 1989 - April 3, 1990 (Box 128, Folder 3)
  - Xerox - Taxonomy, January 24, 1990 - February 10, 1990 (Box 128, Folder 4)
  - Xerox - Ill Requests, undated (Box 128, Folder 5)
  - McClung, P. Great Collection Microfilming Project, Phase III, April 13, 1990 - December 31, 1993 (Box 128)
    NEH Grant period = January 1992 - December 1993
  - Folder 1, April 13, 1990 - December 31, 1993 (Box 128, Folder 6)
  - Folder 2, January 1, 1991 - May 24, 1991 (Box 128, Folder 7)
  - Seznec Xerox: Testbed for Advancing Role of Digital Technology for Library Preservation and Access, January 1, 1992 - September 30, 1992 (Box 128)
  - Connesh? Re: budget L89 - 8506, January 1, 1992 - September 30, 1992 (Box 128, Folder 8)
  - Testbed for Advancing Role of Digital Technology for Library Preservation and Access, January 1, 1992 - September 30, 1992 (Box 128, Folder 9)
  - Xerox L89-8506, January 1, 1992 - September 30, 1992 (Box 128, Folder 10)
  - Kenney, Anne R. Preserving Archival Material through Digital Tech: A Cooperative Demonstration Project, August 1, 1992 - March 31, 1993 (Box 128)
    NYS
  - Preserving Archival Material through Digital Tech: A Coop. Demo. Project Folder 1, February 17, 1992 - May 26, 1993 (Box 128, Folder 11)
    Includes grant approval documents and a catalog record for scanned brittle books.
  - Preserving Archival Material through Digital Tech: A Coop. Demo. Project Folder 2, undated (Box 128, Folder 12)
    Empty, with sticky note reading "Sent original letter to B. White (Townsend); Copies of rest to B. White and R. King"
  - Preserving Archival Material through Digital Tech: A Coop. Demo. Project Folder 3, April 21, 1992 - February 20, 1992 (Box 128, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Big 11 Resolution Scanning, August 1, 1992 - May 26, 1993 (Box 128, Folder 14)
    Includes proposals, various handwritten notes, and correspondence between those involved in project.
  - Dean, J. and Dimunation, M. French Revolution Collections at CU: A Retrospective Conversion and Preservation Project, January 1, 1993 - December 31, 1995 (Box 128)
    Department of Education L89-8303; Grant period January 1, 1993 - December 31, 1995
  - French Revolution Collections at CU: A Retrospective Conversion and Pres. Project - Folder 1, September 24, 1990 - May 9th, 1995 (Box 128, Folder 15)
  - French Revolution Collections at CU: A Retrospective Conversion and Pres. Project - Folder 2, February 1993 (Box 128, Folder 16)
  - McClung, P. Great Collection Microfilming Project IV, March 1, 1993 - February 28, 1996 (Box 128)
    NEH
  - Great Collection Microfilming Project IV Folder 1, March 1, 1993 - February 28, 1996 (Box 128, Folder 17)
  - Great Collection Microfilming Project IV Folder 2, March 1, 1993 - February 28, 1996 (Box 128, Folder 18)
  - Lynn, M. Stuart and Kenney, A. Making of America, July 2, 1993-December 31, 1996 (Box 128)
    Charles E. Culpeper Foundation L89-8511. This project focused on material from 1860 - 1960.
  - Culpeper, 1992 - August 10, 1995 (Box 128, Folder 19)
    Correspondence with the Culpeper foundation; a 1992 report about Phase I of the Cornell/Xerox Commission project; a summer 1992 copy of CIT News about electronic publishing; a Cornell booklet "Creating the Future" from 1991 outlining Cornell's goal for 75 million dollars in donations. Copies of this material were presumably sent to accompany the grant request for the Making of America project.
  - Making of America Folder 1, April 1993 - June 1994 (Box 128, Folder 20)
    Executive summary, a copy of the proposal, and financial reports.
  - Making of America Folder 2, April 1993 - May 12, 1997 (Box 128, Folder 21)
  - Culpeper Correspondence, July 1, 1993 - July 1995 (Box 128, Folder 22)
  - Kenney, A. Preserving and Making Accessible Deteriorating Library Materials through Digital Technology: A Coop. Demo. Project, November 1, 1993 - June 30, 1994 (Box 128)
    NYS L89-8014
  - Preserving and Making Accessible Deteriorating Library Materials through Digital Technology: A Coop. Demo. Project - Folder 1, January 28, 1993-August 25, 1994 (Box 128, Folder 23)
  - Preserving and Making Accessible Deteriorating Library Materials through Digital Technology: A Coop. Demo. Project - Folder 2, July 13, 1993 - July 27, 1994 (Box 128, Folder 24)
  - Preserving and Making Accessible Deteriorating Library Materials through Digital Technology: A Coop. Demo. Project - Folder 3, April 1, 1993 - March 11, 1994 (Box 128, Folder 25)
  - Preserving and Making Accessible Deteriorating Library Materials through Digital Technology: A Coop. Demo. Project - Folder 4, January 1990 - August 17, 1993 (Box 128, Folder 26)
    Contains finished project proposal.
  - Kenney, A. Digital Training for Preservation Administrators, April 1, 1994 - March 31, 1995 (Box 128)
    NYS L89-8016
  - Digital Training for Preservation Administrators - Folder 1, June 23, 1994 - April 25, 1995 (Box 128, Folder 27)
  - Digital Training for Preservation Administrators - Folder 2, 1994-1995 (Box 128, Folder 28)
  - Digital Training for Preservation Administrators - Folder 3, 1994-1995 (Box 128, Folder 29)
  - Digital Training for Preservation Administrators - Folder 4, 1994-1995 (Box 129, Folder 1)
  - Digital Training for Preservation Administrators - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 129, Folder 2)
  - Kenney, A. Digital to Microfilm Conversions, April 1994 - September 1996 (Box 129)
    NEH L89-8302; The order of the folders was determined by the grouping of material that supports each other rather than by date, as old projects are included to provide context for this new project.
  - Digital to Microfilm Conversion - Folder 1, January 12, 1994 - August 8, 1997 (Box 129, Folder 3)
  - Digital to Microfilm Conversion - Folder 2, April 1994 - October 23, 1995 (Box 129, Folder 4)
  - Digital to Microfilm Conversion - Folder 3, December 4, 1994 - August 7, 1997 (Box 129, Folder 5)
  - Digital to Microfilm Conversion - Folder 4, December 5, 1991 -July 18, 1996 (Box 129, Folder 6)
  - Digital to Microfilm Conversion - Folder 5, June 2, 1993-May 27, 1997 (Box 129, Folder 7)
  - Digital to Microfilm Conversion - Folder 6, December 1992 - June 13, 1994 (Box 129, Folder 8)
  - Digital to Micofilm Conversionns - Folder 7, June 1, 1993 - December 23, 1993 (Box 129, Folder 9)
  - Digital to Microfilm Conversion - Folder 8, April 1994 - March 1996 (Box 129, Folder 10)
    Contains the complete project proposal.
  - Digital to Microfilm Conversion - Folder 9, July 25, 1994 - September 25, 1996 (Box 129, Folder 11)
    Contains a bound version of the proposal.
  - Dean, J. Central NY Preservation Technician Training - Failed Proposal, 1994-1995 (Box 129)
  - Central NY Preservation Technician Training Correspondence, February 19, 1992 - December 15, 1995 (Box 129, Folder 12)
  - Berger, B. Icelandic Collection (Fiske) - NEH, January 1, 1995 - December 31, 1997 (Box 129)
    NEH L89-8304
  - Icelandic Collection (Fiske) - Folder 1, February 1992 - April 7, 1994 (Box 129, Folder 13)
    Contains mostly preliminary information from the project's conception.
  - Iceland Grant - Folder 1, October 1992 - 1994 (Box 129, Folder 14)
    Includes a 1992 survey report on the Icelandic collection.
  - Iceland Grant - Folder 2, 1994 (Box 129, Folder 15)
    Includes a project narrative and additional budget information.
  - Iceland Budget Info, 1993 (Box 129, Folder 16)
    Very preliminary budget estimates and drafts, including handwritten calculations.
  - Iceland Budget and Spreadsheets, December 28, 1994 - October 15, 1996 (Box 129, Folder 17)
  - Final Copies Iceland, April 20, 1994 (Box 129, Folder 18)
    Informtion about The Icelandic Educational Network - ISMENNT
  - Iceland Revised Budget, December 15, 1994 (Box 129, Folder 19)
  - Icelandic Collection (Fiske) - Folder 2, December 16, 1994 - January 31, 1998 (Box 129, Folder 20)
    Contains correspondences, monthly transaction statements, and accounting information. Also contains information concerning the "French Revolution Collection Recon (L89-8303).
  - Icelandic Collection (Fiske) - Folder 3, March 31, 1995 - November 20, 1996 (Box 129, Folder 21)
    Contains correspondences, monthly transaction statements, and accounting information.
  - Iceland Budget 1995, April 30, 1995 - August 31, 1995 (Box 129, Folder 22)
  - Iceland Budget 1996, May 31, 1996 - November 20, 1996 (Box 129, Folder 23)
  - Mellon/Iceland, April 8, 1996 - May 16, 1996 (Box 129, Folder 24)
    Correspondence
  - Kenney, A. Vetlesen - Icelandic Collection (Fiske), November 20, 1995 (Box 129, Folder 25)
    G. Under Vetlesen Foundation Contains a new proposal to the G. Under Vetlesen Foundation to supplement the project's NEH grant.
  - Kenney, A. Making of America - Mellon, January 1995 - 1998 (Box 129)
    Andrew W. Mellon Foundation L89-8514
  - Making of America - Mellon - Folder 1, 1995 - January 1998 (Box 129, Folder 26)
    Contains complete grant proposal and final report.
  - Making of America - Mellon - Folder 2, January 31, 1995 - May 10, 1999 (Box 129, Folder 27)
  - Making of America - Mellon - Folder 3, November 9, 1994 - March 22, 1997 (Box 129, Folder 28)
  - Making of America - Mellon - Folder 4, September 12, 1994 - December 15, 1995 (Box 129, Folder 29)
  - Making of America - Mellon - Folder 5, August 16, 1994 - July 11, 1997 (Box 129, Folder 30)
  - Making of America - Mellon - Grant and Publications Folder 1, November 9, 1994 - June 10, 1997 (Box 129, Folder 31)
    Includes newspaper clippings, correspondence, and additional grant proposal material.
  - Making of America - Mellon - Grant and Publications Folder 2, February 3, 1994 - March 1996 (Box 130, Folder 1)
    Contains proposal material and a March 1966 edition of the magazine American Libraries.
  - Making of America - Mellon - Grant and Publications Folder 3, November 9, 1994 - January 1996 (Box 130, Folder 2)
    Contains proposal material and the Kaleidoscope from January 1996.
  - Kenney, A. Commission on Preservation and Access Digital Training Workshop, March 24, 1995 - May 30, 1996 (Box 130)
    CPA L89-8515
  - Commission on Preservation and Access Digital Training Workshop - Folder 1, January 15, 1995 - June 28, 1996 (Box 130, Folder 3)
  - Commission on Preservation and Access Digital Training Workshop Folder 2, Jan 15, 1995 - August 13, 1996 (Box 130, Folder 4)
  - Budgets and Supporting Requirements: Award letter, Proposal; CPA 95-02; OSP 28355, March 1, 1995 - July 23, 1996 (Box 130, Folder 5)
  - Workshop - Funding Request to CLR: Hewlett-Packard and Corporate Sponsors, February 7, 1995 - July 17, 1995 (Box 130, Folder 6)
  - Riedy, Allen J. Mae Fah Luang Agreement; OSP #30312 - The Search and Collection of Materials on Opium and Opiates (Box 130)
    Mae Fah Luang Foundation L81-8504; "The Search and Collection of Materials on Opium and Opiates"
  - Mae Fah Luang Agreement; OSP #30312 - The Search and Collection of Materials on Opium and Opiates, January 29, 1996 - September 9, 2003 (Box 130, Folder 7)
  - Hickerson, Thomas Mellon Icelandic - Icelandic National Digital Library (INDL), 1996 (Box 130)
    Andrew W. Mellon Foundation
  - Mellon Icelandic - Icelandic National Digital Library, June 28, 1996 - June 30, 1996 (Box 130, Folder 8)
  - SagaNet - The Andrew W. Mellon Foundation, July 1, 1997 - June 30, 2000 (Box 130)
    Andrew W. Mellon Foundation L89-8530
  - SagaNet - The Andrew W. Mellon Foundation, January 30, 1997 - July 6, 1998 (Box 130, Folder 9)
  - Kenney, A. Illustrated Book Study (LC), September 12, 1997 - December 31, 1998 (Box 130)
    L89-8305
  - Illustrated Book Study (LC) - Folder 1, November 20, 1996 - June 30, 2000 (Box 130, Folder 10)
  - Illustrated Book Study (LC) - Folder 2, July 31, 1997 - June 30, 1999 (Box 130, Folder 11)
  - Illustrated Book Study (LC) - Folder 3, 1996-1997 (Box 130, Folder 12)
  - Illustrated Book Study (LC) - Folder 4, 1996-1998 (Box 130, Folder 13)
  - Illustrated Book Study (LC) - Folder 5, 1996-1998 (Box 130, Folder 14)
    Mostly correspondence and handwritten notes.
  - Illustrated Book Study (LC) - Folder 6, 1996-1998 (Box 130, Folder 15)
    Sealed Express Mail package?.
  - Kenney, A. Preservation Microfilming and Cataloging of the Dante and Petrarch Collections, May 1998 - April 2001 (Box 130)
  - Dante Grant, May 6, 1997 - undated (Box 130, Folder 16)
    NEH; Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation This folder contains a proposal to the Gladys Krieble Delmas Foundation, but no proposal acceptance information except from the NEH.
  - Preservation Microfilming and Cataloging of the Dante and Petrarch Collections, July 1, 1997 - May 14, 1998 (Box 130, Folder 17)
  - Dean, J. Central NY Technician Training Program, July 1998 - July 2001 (Box 130)
    NYS L89-8026
  - NYS - Technician Training Proposal, January 1998 (Box 130, Folder 18)
  - Applications - '98 - NYS Tech Training, 1998-2000 (Box 130, Folder 19)
  - Budgets and FS10 All Years, 1998-2001 (Box 130, Folder 20)
  - Mann Library - Risk Management of Digital Information, September 1, 1998 - August 31, 1999 (Box 130)
    L89-8524
  - Mann Library - Risk Management of Digital Information - Folder 1, November 5, 1999- January 10, 2000 (Box 130, Folder 21)
  - Mann Library - Risk Management of Digital Information - Folder 2, July 9, 1998 - November 12, 1999 (Box 130, Folder 22)
  - Mann Library - Risk Management of Digital Information - Folder 3, April 1998 - August 1998 (Box 130, Folder 23)
  - Dean, J. IMLS - Design, Plan, Implement Digitial Archiving Program for Image Collection, December 31, 1998 - June 30, 2000; April 1, 2003 - March 31, 2004 (Box 130)
    NYS L89-8308; OSP 34774
  - IMLS - Design, Plan, Implement Digital Archiving Program for Image Collection - Folder 1, July 21, 2003 - February 5, 1999 (Box 130, Folder 24)
  - IMLS - Design, Plan, Implement Digital Archiving Program for Image Collection - Folder 2, 1998-1999 (Box 130, Folder 25)
    Includes newspaper clippings.
  - IMLS - Design, Plan, Implement Digital Archiving Program for Image Collection - Folder 3, 1997-1998 (Box 130, Folder 26)
    Includes an Institue of Museum and Library Services (IMLS) Floppy disc.
  - Kenney, A. Theory in Practice, May 1999 - June 2001 (Box 131)
  - Imagery Tutorial, February 2, 1993 - December 7, 1999 (Box 131, Folder 1)
  - Theory in Practice, June 1998 - January 11, 2001 (Box 131, Folder 2)
  - Department Website, 1998-1999 (Box 131, Folder 3)
  - Kenney, A. NEH Moving Theory into Practice: Digital Imaging for Libraries, May 1, 1999 - June, 2002 (Box 131)
    NEH L89-8310; OSP 33917; DUO 102; The order of the folders was determined by the grouping of material that supports each other rather than by date.
  - NEH Moving Theory into Practice: Digital Imaging for Libraries - Folder 1, July 9, 1998 - June 30, 2002 (Box 131, Folder 4)
  - NEH Moving Theory into Practice: Digital Imaging for Libraries - Folder 2, June 1998 - June 30, 2002 (Box 131, Folder 5)
  - NEH Moving Theory into Practice: Digital Imaging for Libraries - Folder 3, June 1998 - November 19, 2001 (Box 131, Folder 6)
  - Lagoze, C. NSF - Security and Reliability in Component Based Digital Libraries, May 1, 1999 - April 30, 2003 (Box 131)
    NSF L89-8309; OSP 35164
  - NSF - Security and Reliability in Component Based Digital Libraries - Folder 1, March 23, 1998 -July 30, 2003 (Box 131, Folder 7)
  - NSF - Security and Reliability in Component Based Digital Libraries - Folder 2, April 24, 1998 - July 22, 1999 (Box 131, Folder 8)
  - NSF - Security and Reliability in Component Based Digital Libraries - Folder 3, July 7, 1998 - February 1, 1999 (Box 131, Folder 9)
  - Dean, J. Save America's Treasures: Anti Slavery Collection, January 1, 2000 - December 31, 2002 (Box 131)
    NEH L89-8503; L89-8505; L89-8311
  - Save America's Treasures: Anti Slavery Collection, July 27, 1999 - September 12, 2003 (Box 131, Folder 10)
    Includes an official final report of the White House's Save America's Treasures project.
  - Save America's Treasures - Folder 2, January 13, 1999- August 9, 2001 (Box 131, Folder 11)
    Written as a title on the old folder: 1990/1991 L89-8503 Xerox; L89-8505: Subaccount $4300 Comm. Pres
  - Save Our Treasures, May 19, 1999 - January 24, 2000 (Box 131, Folder 12)
  - Harry Littell Antislavery Pamphlets, undated (Box 131, Folder 13)
    Photocopies of antislavery pamphlets. Includes the original film.
  - Anti-Slavery Conservation and Digitization, January 1, 2000 - June 30, 2003 (Box 131, Folder 14)
    L89-8311; OSP 36154
  - Thomas, Sarah E. Making of America Digital Library - Saving America's Treasures, 2000-2003 (Box 131)
    Glady's Brooks Foundation
  - Making of America Digital Library - Saving America's Treasures - Folder 1, October 1, 1996 - May 4, 2000 (Box 131, Folder 15)
  - Making of America Digital Library - Saving America's Treasures - Folder 2, April 6, 2000 - March 6, 2003 (Box 131, Folder 16)
  - Making of America Digital Library - Saving America's Treasures - Folder 3, January 2001 - May 31, 2001 (Box 131, Folder 17)
  - New York State Aide - By Year, 2000-2006 (Box 131)
  - NYS Supplemental Aid 2000-2001, 2000-2001 (Box 131, Folder 18)
    L89-8032
  - NYS Aid 2000-2001, 2000-2001 (Box 131, Folder 19)
    L89-8030
  - NYS Aid 2001/2002, 2001- March 2002 (Box 131, Folder 20)
    L89-8033
  - NYS Aid 2002/2003, 2002-March 2003 (Box 131, Folder 21)
    L89-8036; OSP 42084; Includes NYS guideline and application informatin for 2002-2003.
  - NYS Aid 2003/2004, 2003- March 2004 (Box 131, Folder 22)
    L89-8038
  - NYS Aid 2004/2005, 2004-March 2005 (Box 131, Folder 23)
    L89-8040
  - NYS Aid 2005/2006, 2005-March 2006 (Box 131, Folder 24)
    L89-8042
  - Thomas, Sarah E. Project Harvest, January 1, 2001 - December 31, 2001 (Box 131)
    Andrew W. Mellon Foundation L89-8502
  - Project Harvest, October 13, 2000 - January 12, 2001 (Box 131, Folder 25)
    Contains the project proposal.
  - Berger, B. Witchcraft Collection: A Project to Preserve and Enhance Access at Cornell, July 1, 2001 - June 30, 2004 (Box 131)
    NEH L89-8312
  - Witchcraft Collection: A Project to Preserve and Enchance Access at Cornell - Folder 1, 1996-1999 (Box 131, Folder 26)
  - Witchcraft Collection: A Project to Preserve and Enchance Access at Cornell - Folder 2, 1996 - June 1, 2001 (Box 131, Folder 27)
  - Witchcraft Collection: A Project to Preserve and Enchance Access at Cornell - Folder 3, 1996 - July 1, 2000 (Box 131, Folder 28)
  - Witchcraft Collection: A Project to Preserve and Enchance Access at Cornell - Folder 4, May 25, 1999 - December 23, 2004 (Box 131, Folder 29)
  - Witchcraft Collection: A Project to Preserve and Enchance Access at Cornell - Folder 5, July 1, 2000 (Box 131, Folder 30)
    Contains preliminary proposal forms, the grant proposal, and the application.
  - Witchcraft Bills, October 16, 2003 - July 29, 2003 (Box 131, Folder 31)